jeedoo.com 2019-06-16

# jeedoo.com - Datenschutz

For jeedoo, the protection of personal data has the highest priority. We would therefore like to inform you here how we protect your privacy when you provide us with your personal data. In addition to the self-evident compliance with the legal data protection regulations in Germany, we would like to commit ourselves with these instructions to a responsible handling of your data, so that your privacy is protected at all times. It is important to us that you feel secure when visiting our website.

Under the point "Responsible body" we inform you first about the person responsible, the data protection officer and any contact possibilities. Under "General information on the use of the Internet pages" jeedoo.com '"we will inform you then on all sides applicable information. Under the heading "Additional information for customers" and "Further information for retailers", information will be listed that applies specifically to the respective user group. Under the point "Rights of the persons concerned" we would like to inform you about your rights as data subjects within the meaning of the GDPR.

A. Responsible body  
B. General information on the use of the website "jeedoo.com"   
C. Further notes for customers  
D. Further information for dealers  
E. Rights of data subjects

Should you have any further questions regarding the collection, processing and use of your personal data or individual processes, our data protection officer will be pleased to assist you with further inquiries under the following contact options.  
If there are any significant changes to the privacy policy, we will notify you via e-mail.

## A. Responsible body

**I. Name and address of the person responsible**  
The person responsible within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation and other national data protection laws of the member states as well as other data protection regulations is:  
JUGSCHUG SL  
DOMICILIO: Avda Touroperador Finnmatkat, Num. 9 SOCIAL: Puerta 21  
Aptos Sunny Golf - Maspalomas  
35100 San Bartolome de Tirajana  
Las Palmas de Gran Canaria  
Número de Identificación Dical Definitivo: B76140409 

**II. Name and address of the data protection officer**  
For any questions concerning the collection, processing or use of your personal data, please contact our data protection officer, who can be contacted via the following addresses:

JUGSCHUG SL  
DOMICILIO: Avda Touroperador Finnmatkat, Num. 9 SOCIAL: Puerta 21  
Aptos Sunny Golf - Maspalomas  
35100 San Bartolome de Tirajana  
Las Palmas de Gran Canaria  
Número de Identificación Dical Definitivo: B76140409  
Contact via e-mail: info@jeedoo.com

## B. General information on the use of the website "jeedoo.com"

We collect and use personal data of our users primarily only for the purpose for which the data was provided to us, in particular for the processing of your order, to send you ordered newsletter or as far as to provide a functional website and our content and services is required.  
For the procedures in detail:

I. Provision of the website jeedoo.com and creation of logfiles 

1\. Description and scope of data processing  
Each time our website is accessed, our system automatically collects data and information from the computer system of the calling computer. The following data will be collected if they are transmitted due to your browser setting:

1\. Information about the browser type and version used   
2\. The operating system of the user  
3\. The IP address of the user  
4\. Date and time of access  
5\. The last website from which the system of the user comes to our website  
The data is stored at short notice in the logfiles of our system. A storage of this data together with other personal data of the user does not take place.

2\. Legal basis for data processing  
The legal basis for the temporary storage of data and log files is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO.

3\. Purpose of the data processing  
The temporary storage of the IP address by the system is necessary to allow delivery of the website to the computer of the user. To do this, the user's IP address must be kept for the duration of the session. Storage in log files is done to ensure the functionality of the website. In addition, the data is used to optimize the website and to ensure the security of our information technology systems. For these purposes, our legitimate interest in the processing of data pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO.

4\. Duration of storage  
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection.

5\. Opposition and removal possibility  
The collection of data for the provision of the website and the storage of the data in log files is essential for the operation of the website. There is consequently no contradiction on the part of the user.

## II. Use of cookies

1\. Description and scope of data processing  
To optimize the ordering process, our website uses cookies. Cookies are text files that are stored in the Internet browser or the Internet browser on the user's computer system. When a user visits a website, a cookie may be stored on the user's operating system. This cookie contains a characteristic string that allows the browser to be uniquely identified when the website is reopened.

With the help of such cookies, for example, your shopping carts or shopping lists are stored to make your next order easier. After completing the order and when you visit our website again, you will be recognized as a customer with the help of a corresponding cookie and this will facilitate a new order process. Most browsers have features that can refuse to accept cookies or, after completing a visit to an Internet site, delete their accepted cookies. Without cookies, you can use certain features of the website, such as:

B. in the online shop does not use.  
We use cookies to make our website more user-friendly. Some elements of our website require that the calling browser be identified even after a page break.

The following data are stored and transmitted in the cookies by way of example:  
1\. last accessed articles  
2\. Article in a shopping cart or the desire for sale

In addition, we use cookies on our website that allow an analysis of users' browsing behavior.

In this way, the following data can be transmitted by way of example:  
1\. Entered search terms  
2\. Frequency of page views 3. Use of website functions

The data of the users collected in this way are pseudonymized by technical precautions. Therefore, an assignment of the data to the calling user is no longer possible. The data will not be stored together with other personal data of the users.

Users are informed about the use of cookies for analysis purposes in the privacy policy. In this context, there is also an indication of how the storage of cookies in the browser settings can be prevented.

2\. Legal basis for data processing  
The legal basis for the processing of personal data using cookies is Article 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO.

3\. Purpose of the data processing  
The purpose of using technically necessary cookies is to facilitate the use of websites for users. Some features of our website can not be offered without the use of cookies. For these, it is necessary that the browser is recognized even after a page break.  
The use of the analysis cookies is for the purpose of improving the quality of our website and its contents. Through the analysis cookies, we learn how the website is used and so we can constantly optimize our offer. The exact purpose of use can be found in the comments on the web analysis.  
For these purposes, our legitimate interest in the processing of personal data pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO.

4\. Duration of storage, objection and disposal options  
Cookies are stored on the computer of the user and transmitted by this to our site. Therefore, as a user, you have full control over the use of cookies. By changing the settings in your internet browser, you can disable or restrict the transmission of cookies. Already saved cookies can be deleted at any time. This can also be done automatically. If cookies are disabled for our website, it may not be possible to use all the functions of the website to the full.

## III. Web analysis involving various partners 

1\. Scope of processing of personal data  
We use various tools on our website to analyze the surfing behavior of our users. In detail:

1a. Google Analytics  
In addition, our website uses Google Analytics: a web analytics service provided by Google inc. Which uses so-called "cookies". As described above, these are text files that are stored on your computer and allow an analysis of your use of the website.  
If individual pages of our website are called, the following data is stored in particular:  
1\. Two bytes of the IP address of the calling system of the user  
2\. Information about the operating system of the calling system  
3\. Information about the browser  
4\. The website called  
5\. The website from which the user accessed the website (so-called referrer URL)  
6\. The subpages that are called from the called website   
7\. The length of stay on the website  
8\. Date and time of your visit to our website

The information generated by this text file about the use of our website is transmitted to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of our website, to compile reports on website activity for website operators and to provide other services related to website activity and internet usage. If this is required by law or if third parties process this data on behalf of Google, Google will also pass on this information to these third parties. This usage is anonym or pseudomized. More information can be found directly on Google.  
If you wish that Google Analytics does not have insight into your usage behavior, as just described, you can integrate a deactivation add-on into your browser.  
More information about this add-on can be found at: https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/.  
By using our offers, you agree to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner described here and for the purpose stated above. Please note that Google has its own privacy policies that are independent of ours. We assume no responsibility or liability for these policies and procedures. Please check http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/ before using our website.

2\. Legal basis for the processing of personal data  
Legal basis for the processing of the data is in the presence of the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.  
At the same time, additional legal basis for the processing of users' personal data is Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO.

3\. Purpose of the data processing  
The processing of users' personal data enables us to analyze the surfing behavior of our users. By analyzing the data obtained, we are able to compile information about the use of the individual components of our website. This helps us to constantly improve our website and its user-friendliness. For these purposes, our legitimate interest lies in the processing of the data according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. The anonymisation of the IP address sufficiently takes into account the interest of users in the protection of their personal data.

4\. Duration of storage  
The data will be deleted as soon as they are no longer needed for our recording purposes.

5\. Opposition and removal possibility  
We offer our users the option of opting out of the analysis process on our website. For this you must follow the named links. In this way, another cookie is set on their system that signals our system not to store the user's data. If the user deletes the corresponding cookie in the meantime from his own system, he must set the opt-out cookie again.

## IV. Social login

1\. Scope of processing of personal data  
If you make use of the possibility of social login via the social network Facebook, the following data will be transmitted to us by this social network:  
Facebook:  
• E-mail address  
• Surname  
• Gender  
These data are stored with us and used in accordance with this privacy policy. Jeedoo.com does not share data with social networks.

2\. Legal basis for the processing of personal data  
Legal basis for the processing of the data is in the presence of the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.  
Finally, an additional legal basis for the processing of the personal data of users is Article 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO.

3\. Purpose of the data processing  
The use of the data is required, on the one hand, for the provision of certain content and services on our website and, on the other, for the fulfillment of a contract with the user or for the performance of pre-contractual measures. For these purposes, our legitimate interest lies in the processing of data according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. The anonymisation of the IP address sufficiently takes into account the interest of users in the protection of their personal data.

4\. Duration of storage  
The data will be deleted as soon as they are no longer needed for our recording purposes.

5\. Opposition and removal possibility  
As a user, you have the option of canceling the registration at any time. You can change the data stored about you at any time. Simply log into your customer account or contact our support with your request.  
If the data is required to fulfill a contract or to carry out pre-contractual measures, premature deletion of the data is only possible, unless contractual or legal obligations preclude deletion.

## V. Newsletter

1\. Description and scope of data processing  
On our website you can subscribe to a free newsletter. The data from the input mask are transmitted to us when registering for the newsletter.  
1\. name  
2\. E-mail address  
3\. Date and time of registration  
After registration, we will inform you regularly by e-mail about current offers and promotions. To register, we need your e-mail address. If you provide us with further data, we will use this and other information. a. to address you personally.  
After submitting the registration form, you will receive an e-mail from us with a request for confirmation (double-opt-in). Your registration will not take effect until you click on the link in this e-mail. If you do not confirm the registration, your data will be deleted. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time. To do this, use the unsubscribe link that is specified in each e-mail or the corresponding function in the membership area.  
If you have purchased via jeedoo.com or have requested offers, we will also use your e- mail address given in connection with the purchase by e-mail to advertise your own similar offers. In such a case, the newsletter will only send direct mail for your own similar goods or services.

2\. Legal basis for data processing  
Legal basis for the processing of the data after registration for the newsletter by the user is in the presence of a consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.  
The legal basis for sending the newsletter as a result of the sale of goods or services is § 7 Abs. 3 UWG.

3\. Purpose of the data processing  
The collection of the user's e-mail address serves to deliver the newsletter. The collection of other personal data in the context of the registration process serves to prevent misuse of the services or the email address used.

4\. Duration of storage  
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. The e-mail address of the user is therefore stored at least as long as the subscription to the newsletter is active. After that, the addresses will be kept for up to 30 days in the newsletter database in order to prevent misuse of the discount grant by repeatedly logging out and subscribing to the newsletter before the e-mail addresses are finally deleted.

5\. Opposition and removal possibility  
Subscription to the newsletter may be terminated at any time by the user concerned. Please inform us of your cancellation in text form to the following named address: info@jeedoo.com or use the link to complete deregistration from the newsletter, which is indicated in each e-mail. This also allows a revocation of the consent to the storage of the personal data collected during the registration process.

## VI. Abusive use of the website

1\. Description and scope of data processing  
If it is used to investigate abuse of the platform for which a legal action is necessary or there is a legal obligation to disclose, personal data will be forwarded to authorities (in particular law enforcement authorities and tax authorities), our legal defense and, if necessary, to third parties. Disclosure may also occur if it serves to enforce our Terms and Conditions or other agreements or is required by law or regulation or court order.

2\. Legal basis of data processing  
The legal basis for processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. 

3\. Purpose of the data processing  
Data processing is imperative to ensure the security of our information technology systems and processes as well as to meet legal and regulatory requirements. For these purposes, our legitimate interest in the processing of data pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO.

4\. Duration of storage  
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection.

5\. Opposition and removal possibility  
The processing of the data in the event of misuse of rights is mandatory in order to prevent the misuse of the services provided and the impairment of the rights of third parties. There is consequently no contradiction on the part of the user.

C. Further notes for customers  
We only store your personal data if you let us know. This data, in particular name, address and e-mail address, we need to process your order in the online shop or if you order, for example, a newsletter.  
The data collection takes place by entering your data in the respective input mask of the order or contact form.  
For the procedures in detail:  
I. Registration  
1\. Description and scope of data processing

On our website, we offer users the opportunity to register by providing personal information. The data is entered into an input mask and transmitted to us and stored. The following data is collected during the registration process:  
1\. first name  
2\. Surname  
3\. User  
4\. E-mail address  
5\. Password, encrypted  
6\. Consent to terms and conditions and data protection, including the time of approval   
7\. Optionally, if a newsletter has been ordered, incl. Time of agreement

In particular, if you have created a jeedoo account, we will use the e-mail address provided there to provide you with important service information or changes to your customer account. In addition, a transfer to third parties u. a. in the frame described below.  
In addition, the consent of the user is obtained for processing this data. 2. Legal basis for data processing  
Legal basis for the processing of the data is in the presence of the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.  
At the same time, the registration serves the fulfillment of a contract of which the user is a party or the implementation of pre-contractual measures, so additional legal basis for the processing of the data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO.

3\. Purpose of the data processing  
The registration of the user is required on the one hand for the provision of certain contents and services, such as the processing of the order, on our website.  
In addition, the registration of the user to fulfill a contract with the user or to carry out pre-contractual measures is required.

4\. Duration of storage  
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection.  
If the data collected does not serve to conclude a contract with the user, this is the case for the data collected during the registration process, if the registration on our website is canceled or modified.  
With regard to data collected during the registration process for the purpose of fulfilling a contract or for carrying out pre-contractual measures, this is the case if the data are no longer necessary for the performance of the contract. Even after the conclusion of the contract, there may be a need to store personal data of the contracting party in order to comply with contractual or legal obligations, such as those arising from the limitation periods for warranty claims or tax-related retention obligations.

5\. Opposition and removal possibility  
As a user, you have the option of canceling the registration at any time. You can change the data stored about you at any time. Simply log in to your customer account or contact support with your request.  
If the data is required to fulfill a contract or to carry out pre-contractual measures, premature deletion of the data is only possible, unless contractual or legal obligations preclude deletion.

## II. Order processing

1\. Description and scope of data processing  
On jeedoo.com, Jugschug SL, as operator of the website, is always the seller of the goods. On our side, however, various natural and legal persons and partnerships ("commercial users and private users") are discontinuing supply of goods. In their function as suppliers, these are named as such in the offer presentation under "Supplier" and are listed in the order processing.  
It is therefore a transfer to third parties u. a. in the framework described below: Suppliers  
In cases where suppliers, companies or individuals run their own shop on jeedoo or they offer their products via jeedoo.com, they do so in their own name. In order to be able to guarantee a fast processing of your order as well as the complaint handling, it is therefore essential to involve the suppliers in the processes. In addition to the transfer of the necessary data to fulfill the legal transaction in the context of order processing, the suppliers therefore also have access to the complaint system and support system and the order processing and can see the local news and detailed information on the order such as your address data (for more information, see below) ,  
Other service providers  
Furthermore, it may be necessary, for example, to transfer your data to service providers, such as Billing agencies and carriers, to handle your request. In particular, with regard to the sending of transactional e-mails, this can lead to the transmission and storage of individual information to a server in the United States of America. However, such a transfer of the data to third parties always takes place only in the context of legal regulations or order data processing.  
In addition, the consent of the user is obtained for processing this data.

2\. Legal basis for data processing  
Legal basis for the processing of the data is in the presence of the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.  
At the same time, the registration serves the fulfillment of a contract of which the user is a party or the implementation of pre-contractual measures, so additional legal basis for the processing of the data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO.

3\. Purpose of the data processing  
The registration of the user is required on the one hand for the provision of certain contents and services, such as the processing of the order, on our website.  
In addition, the registration of the user to fulfill a contract with the user or to carry out pre-contractual measures is required.

4\. Duration of storage  
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection.  
If the data collected does not serve to conclude a contract with the user, this is the case for the data collected during the registration process, if the registration on our website is canceled or modified.  
With regard to data collected during the registration process for the purpose of fulfilling a contract or for carrying out pre-contractual measures, this is the case if the data are no longer necessary for the performance of the contract. Even after the conclusion of the contract, there may be a need to store personal data of the contracting party in order to comply with contractual or legal obligations, such as those arising from the limitation periods for warranty claims or tax-related retention obligations.

5\. Opposition and removal possibility  
As a user, you have the option of canceling the registration at any time. You can change the data stored about you at any time. Simply log into your customer account or contact our support with your request.  
If the data is required to fulfill a contract or to carry out pre-contractual measures, premature deletion of the data is only possible, unless contractual or legal obligations preclude deletion.

## III. Payment services and payment procedures, credit check

1\. Description and scope of data processing  
To settle payments, jeedoo has used heidelpay GmbH as "payment service provider". The payment service provider is authorized to offer payment services and are regulated by the German Federal Financial Supervisory Authority (BaFin) as a payment institution i. Pursuant to Section 1 (1) (5) of the Payment Services Supervision Act ("ZAG"). It is listed on BaFin's public payment register on its website.  
The payment service provider offers payment services for the execution of contracts for the purchase and sale of products between the customer and jeedoo, which are closed on the website jeedoo.com. The payment service provider accept the payments of the customers by means of the different payment methods for the merchant in their own account with a bank and pay out the money from the sale of the products to jeedoo.  
For the payment itself, customers have the option of either the payment options provided by jeedoo.com or the payment methods offered by heidelpay GmbH.

The methods of payment provided include, but are not limited to, payment by credit card and Sofortüberweisung.  
The data that you enter for the purpose of payment in the check-out will be processed in the context of your order and the related payment processing and in this connection, if necessary, to third parties, especially the payment providers, passed.  
In addition, for individual payment methods where there is a risk of payment default or increased risk of fraud, a SCHUFA and / or Bürgel query or fraud prevention measures may be taken by the payment service provider or one of the connected payment providers in individual cases, if you as the buyer are using the appropriate payment methods, such as "purchase on account" or other payment methods. With the payment method heidelpay GmbH, heidelpay GmbH examines and evaluates the data provided by the customer and maintains a legitimate reason for data exchange with other companies and credit rating agencies. If the creditworthiness of the customer can not be guaranteed, Heidelpay GmbH can also deny the customer the payment methods and must point out alternative payment options. As part of the payment by credit card fraud prevention measures are also taken.

2\. Legal basis for data processing  
The legal basis for processing the data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO. At the same time, additional legal basis for the processing of users' personal data is Art. 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO.

3\. Purpose of the data processing  
The processing of the data in the course of payment processing is required in particular for keeping the order processing on our website. It thus serves to fulfill a contract with the user or to carry out pre-contractual measures.  
The individual SCHUFA and / or Bürgel queries or measures for fraud prevention in the case of credit card transactions also serve the purpose of minimizing the risk of payment default and preventing credit card misuse. For these purposes, our legitimate interest lies in the processing of data according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO.

4\. Duration of storage  
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. In the case of data collected for the performance of a contract or for the performance of pre-contractual measures, this is the case if the data are no longer required for the performance of the contract. Even after the conclusion of the contract, there may be a need to store personal data of the contractor, in order to meet contractual or legal obligations, as they are Example from the statute of limitations for warranty claims or from tax-related retention obligations result.

5\. Opposition and removal possibility  
Until the data is finally collected by sending the order, you can change the data yourself, remove it from the input mask or change the payment method according to your wishes. Afterwards the processing is absolutely necessary for the processing of the order. There is consequently no contradiction on the part of the user.

## IV. Contact form, e-mail contact and use of the support system

1\. Description and scope of data processing  
As a user of our website you have the opportunity to contact us in various ways (eg by telephone, by contact form, e-mail, fax or letter or by using the support system). If you make the contact possible, all relevant data for the conversation will be collected. These include in particular:  
1\. name  
2\. E-mail address  
3\. Billing / shipping address  
4\. Transaction data  
5\. If necessary. Date of birth and phone number  
6\. When contacting via the contact form: IP address  
The user's personal information submitted during the process is stored and used to process the conversation. A passing on to third parties takes place. a. in the framework described below:  
For example, it may be necessary to transfer your data to service providers such as: As billing agencies or carriers to pass on your request.  
In some other cases, as with the suppliers on jeedoo.com, companies or individuals operate their own shop or they offer their products via jeedoo.com. In order to be able to guarantee a quick processing of your order or complaint processing, it is therefore essential to involve the suppliers in the processes. In addition to the transfer of the necessary data to fulfill the legal transaction in the context of order processing, the suppliers also have access to the support system and can see the news about the tickets there, as long as we invite the intervening supplier into the conversation.  
In the context of the order, the processing of the data is referred to this privacy policy and your consent is obtained by order.

2\. Legal basis for data processing  
Legal basis for the processing of the data is in the presence of the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.  
The legal basis for the processing of the data is additionally Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. If the e-mail contact aims to conclude a contract, then additional legal basis for the processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO.

3\. Purpose of the data processing  
The processing of personal data from the input mask serves to process the contact. The other personal data processed during the sending process serve to prevent misuse of the contact form and the security of our information technology Ensure systems. For these purposes, our legitimate interest lies in the processing of data according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO.

4\. Duration of storage  
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. For the personal data from the input form of the contact form and those sent by e-mail, this is the case when the respective conversation with the user has ended. The conversation is ended when it can be inferred from the circumstances that the relevant facts have been finally clarified.

5\. Opposition and removal possibility  
The user has the possibility at any time to revoke his consent to the processing of the personal data. The conversation can then possibly not be continued. Please contact customer service with your request.

## D. Further information for dealers

I. Registration and use of the platform

1\. Description and scope of data processing  
On our website, we offer suppliers the opportunity to register by providing personal information. The data is entered into an input mask, transmitted to us and stored. Suppliers are then given the opportunity, by processing the data, to list products on jeedoo.com, distribute them to private and business customers of jeedoo.com. To process the data, a consent of the user is obtained by means of a notice in the GTC.  
A passing on to third parties takes place. a. in the following cases:  
For the disclosure of your data to the end customer in the ordering process, for the provision of marketing services or if this serves to clarify a misuse of the platform or appears to be necessary for the prosecution or legal defense of the provider. Insofar as we have concrete indications of unlawful or abusive behavior, on request of certain public authorities or in the case of warnings from industrial property rights, copyright or competition law, the provider may submit personal data to law enforcement agencies, tax authorities or authorities who are prosecuting fines and, if necessary, . to third parties claiming a violation of their rights. We are not obliged to check beforehand whether the claim of the third party is justified. Disclosure may occur even if it serves to enforce the agreement or is required by law, regulation or court order

2\. Legal basis for data processing  
Legal basis for the processing of the data is in the presence of the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR.  
At the same time, the registration serves the fulfillment of a contract of which the user is a party or the implementation of pre-contractual measures, so additional legal basis for the processing of the data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO.  
Finally, as a further legal basis for the processing, Article 6 (1) lit. to quantify DSGVO.

3\. Purpose of the data processing  
The registration of the user is required for the provision of certain content and services on our website. In addition, the registration of the user to fulfill a contract with the user or to carry out pre-contractual measures is required. Finally, data processing can become imperative to ensure the security of our information technology systems and processes as well as to meet legal and regulatory requirements. For these purposes, our legitimate interest in the processing of data pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO.

4\. Duration of storage  
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection.  
If the data collected does not serve to conclude a contract with the user, this is the case for the data collected during the registration process, if the registration on our website is canceled or modified.  
With regard to data collected during the registration process for the purpose of fulfilling a contract or for carrying out pre-contractual measures, this is the case if the data are no longer necessary for the performance of the contract. Even after the conclusion of the contract, there may be a need to store personal data of the contracting party in order to comply with contractual or legal obligations.

5\. Opposition and removal possibility  
As a user, you have the option of canceling the registration at any time. You can change the data stored about you at any time. Simply log in to your customer account or contact Marketplace Support with your request.  
If the data is required to fulfill a contract or to carry out pre-contractual measures, premature deletion of the data is only possible, unless contractual or legal obligations preclude deletion.  
E. Rights of data subjects  
If you process personal data, you are i.S.d. DSGVO and you have the following rights, as far as no exceptions are relevant, to:  
1\. Right to information  
You, as the affected person, have the right to ask the person responsible for a confirmation as to whether personal data relating to you will be processed; If this is the case, you have a right to be informed about this personal data and to the information listed in detail in Art. 15 GDPR.

2\. Right to rectification  
Moreover, as the data subject, you have the right to demand from the person responsible without delay the correction of incorrect personal data concerning you and possibly the completion of incomplete personal data (Art. 16 GDPR).

3\. Right to restriction of processing  
Furthermore, the data subject has the right to demand that the person responsible for the processing be restricted if one of the conditions listed in Art. 18 GDPR is fulfilled, eg. For example, if the data subject has objected to processing for the duration of the review by the controller.

4\. Right to cancellation  
Finally, as the data subject, you have the right to require the person responsible to delete your personal data without delay if one of the reasons detailed in Art. 17 GDPR is applicable, eg. For example, if the data is no longer needed for the purposes pursued (right to delete).

5\. Right to information  
If you have the right of rectification, erasure or restriction of processing to the controller, he / she is obliged to notify all recipients to whom your personal data have been disclosed of this correction or deletion of the data or restriction of processing, unless: this proves to be impossible or involves a disproportionate effort.  
You have a right to the person responsible to be informed about these recipients.

6\. Right to Data Portability  
You have the right to receive personally identifiable information you provide to the controller in a structured, common and machine-readable format. You also have the right to transfer this information to another person without hindrance by the controller to whom the personal data has been provided, provided that:  
1\. the processing on a consent acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR or Art. 9 para. 2 lit. a DSGVO or on a contract acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO is based and  
2\. the processing is done using automated procedures.  
In exercising this right, you also have the right to obtain that your personal data relating to you are transmitted directly from one person to another, insofar as this is technically feasible. Freedoms and rights of other persons may not be affected.  
The right to data portability does not apply to the processing of personal data necessary for the performance of a task in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority delegated to the controller.

7\. Right to object  
You have the right at any time, for reasons that arise from your particular situation, against the processing of your personal data, which pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. e or f DSGVO takes an objection; this also applies to profiling based on these provisions.

The controller will no longer process the personal data concerning you unless he can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for processing that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is for the purpose of enforcing, exercising or defending legal claims.  
If the personal data relating to you are processed for direct marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time to the processing of your personal data for the purpose of such advertising; this also applies to profiling insofar as it is associated with such direct mail.  
If you object to processing for direct marketing purposes, your personal data will no longer be processed for these purposes.  
Regardless of Directive 2002/58 / EC, you have the option, in the context of the use of information society services, of exercising your right to object through automated procedures that use technical specifications.

8\. Right to revoke the data protection consent declaration  
You have the right to revoke your data protection declaration at any time. The revocation of consent does not affect the legality of the processing carried out on the basis of the consent until the revocation.

9\. Automated decision on a case-by-case basis, including profiling  
You have the right not to be subjected to a decision based solely on automated processing - including profiling - that will have legal effect or similarly affect you in a similar manner. This does not apply if the decision  
1\. is required for the conclusion or fulfillment of a contract between you and the person responsible,  
2\. is permitted by Union or Member State legislation to which the controller is subject, and where such legislation contains appropriate measures to safeguard your rights and freedoms and legitimate interests, or  
3\. with your express consent.  
However, these decisions must not be based on special categories of personal data under Art. 9 (1) GDPR, unless Art. 9 (2) lit. a or g DSGVO applies and reasonable measures have been taken to protect the rights and freedoms as well as your legitimate interests.  
With regard to the cases referred to in (1) and (3), the person responsible shall take appropriate measures to uphold the rights and freedoms and their legitimate interests, including at least the right to obtain the intervention of a person by the controller, to express his / her own position and heard on challenge of the decision.

10\. Right to complain to a supervisory authority  
Without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy, any data subject shall have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority if the data subject considers that the processing of personal data concerning him / her violates the GDPR (Article 77 GDPR). The data subject may assert this right with a supervisory authority in the Member State of his or her residence, place of work or place of alleged infringement. In North Rhine-Westphalia the responsible supervisory authority is:  
Country Commissioner for Data Protection and Freedom of Information of Spain
